# **Sergey Kambalin**

Senior Software Developer

kambalin@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sergeykambalin

Professional software developer with 10+ years of experience in TypeScript, JavaScript and PHP development. Always trying to keep abreast of technology trends and best programming practices. Productive in both team-based and self-managed projects.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, GraphQL

React, React Native, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, GraphQL-PHP, Express Frameworks Webpack, Babel, Storybook, Lerna, NPM, Yarn, Composer, Docker

Jest, Enzyme, Testing Library

## **Professional Experience**

**Evolution Gaming** Minsk, Belarus Nov 2019 - present

Senior Software Developer

- Migrated a complex legacy project from JavaScript/AngularJS to TypeScript/React with unit testing on Jest
- Refactored the legacy project from monolithic to modular structure
- · Participate in interviewing and mentoring programs

Technology stack:

- · TypeScript, JavaScript
- React & Redux ecosystem
- · Babel, Webpack, Storybook, Lerna + Yarn Workspaces
- · Jest, Enzyme, React/DOM Testing Library

**IOLA** Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan Oct 2018 - Nov 2019

Senior Software Developer/Architect

- Designed, developed and successfully delivered React Native iOS and Android application
- · Designed and developed modular GraphQL server on PHP
- · Developed UI kit based on Web Components

Technology stack:

- · React, React Native, GraphQL, Web Components
- Babel, Webpack, Storybook, Lerna
- SlimPHP, GraphQL-PHP

Klika Tech LLC Minsk, Belarus

Senior Software Developer/Team Lead

- Took part in various company projects as a full stack JavaScript/PHP developer
- · Led a team developing JavaScript SDK for a customer which is used across many projects
- · Participated in interviewing and mentoring programs
- Was the company's frontend community leader

Technology stack:

- · React, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Mocha, Chai, Sinon
- PHP, PHPUnit, NodeJs, Sails, Express

Skalfa Asia LLC Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

Senior Software Developer/Team Lead

· Led design and development of a hybrid IOS/Android application based on Ionic Framework and SlimPHP

· Was a lead developer in a team designing and developing open source website platforms: Oxwall, Skadate

• Led development of native iOS application for online dating platform: Skadate

Software Developer Jul 2010 - Dec 2012

• Took part in the development of a high load SaaS solution: Wall.fm

Junior Software Developer Mar 2009 - Jul 2010

· Developed various modules for online dating platform: Skadate

#### Education

### **International University of Kyrgyzstan**

Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

Bachelor of Information Technology, Software Engineer Sep 2003 - Jun 2007

Oct 2016 - Sep 2018

Dec 2012 - Sep 2016